A Guide to the James Whitcomb Riley Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7133-h
James Whitcomb Riley Collection 1893-1916
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7133-h
ca. 25 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [1967 October 4] 1968 January 25
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Poem, "Almost Beyond Endurance", TMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "The Toy-Balloon", n.d.; TMsS, 1 p.
- Letters
  - James Whitcomb Riley to [Edward W.] Bok, 1895 Apr 10; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Whitcomb Riley to Edward W. Bok, 1895 May 11; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Whitcomb Riley to Edward W. Bok, 1895 Jun 1; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Whitcomb Riley to Edward W. Bok, 1896 Jan 28; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Whitcomb Riley to Edward W. Bok, 1902 Nov 14; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Whitcomb Riley to Edward W. Bok, 1903 May 15; ALS, 1 p.
  - [ James Whitcomb Riley] to Clara E. Laughlin, 1897 Dec 16; Envelope
- Photographs
  - James Whitcomb Riley, seated, n.d.; Magazine photo
  - James Whitcomb Riley, head and shoulders, Magazine photo
  - James Whitcomb Riley, head and shoulders, Photo from book
- Miscellaneous
  - Quotation from "In Swimming-Time" by James Whitcomb Riley, 1893 Aug 10; Clipping
  - Article about James Whitcomb Riley, [1895]; Clipping
  - Article, "James Whitcomb Riley's 'Home Folks' " by John F. Mitchell, Jr., 1902 Jan; Clipping
  - Poem, "His Pa's Romance" by James Whitcomb Riley, 1903 Jan; Clipping
  - Four poems by James Whitcomb Riley, 1903 Mar; Clipping (2 copies)
  - Article, "James Whitcomb Riley," by Paul M. Pearson, 1906 Oct; Clipping
  - Article about James Whitcomb Riley, [l916] Jul 22; Clipping
  - Article, "Books and Bookmen," by James MacArthur, re: James Whitcomb Riley, Clipping (2 copies)
  - Article, "Mr. Riley as a Public Speaker," by George C. Hitt, n.d.; Clipping
  - Article, "The Hoosier Poet" by Rufus R. Wilson, n.d.; Clipping